<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BeatVortex – Releases</title><link>/blog/releases/</link><description>Recent content in Releases on BeatVortex</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Alpha 3.3 Release</title><link>/blog/2020/06/22/alpha-3.3-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/06/22/alpha-3.3-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release adds some new features and fixes to the &lt;a href="../../updates/v0.3.2">previous alpha release&lt;/a> including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Added &lt;em>preview&lt;/em> support for automatic updates for BeatMods mods!
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This has barely been tested, and we're in uncharted territory, so only enable this one if you're truly brave.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enable them from the Settings page then click &lt;em>Check for Updates&lt;/em> in your Mods list to check for updates from BeatMods&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Session caching: we've started integrating caching support for BeatMods and BeatSaver.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This should pretty dramatically cut down the load on those services by caching requests for the current session.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create your own playlists: You can now select any number of BeatSaver-installed maps from your Mods list and create a playlist from them
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can save your playlist file locally, or immediately install it into your game (or both!)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automatic game upgrade detection
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>BeatVortex will now detect when Beat Saber has been updated since the last time you ran the game (with BSIPA installed) and offer to disable your mods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can then check for updates and re-enable mods once you know they're compatible.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extra warnings and detections: BeatVortex will now try and warn you about some common mistakes/errors, such as when mods are going to be &lt;a href="../../docs/usage/bsipa">yeeted&lt;/a>, when you have conflicting update setups, or when installing the wrong files.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>BSIPA Config Tweaks: check the &lt;a href="../../docs/usage/bsipa">new BSIPA docs page&lt;/a> to learn more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Playlist Management improvements
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>There's been a lot of behind-the-scenes updates to the Playlists manager that should make it snappier and stabler.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We've also fixed the pretty huge bug where the map list would be for the wrong playlist.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As with &lt;a href="../../updates/v0.3.1">v0.3.1&lt;/a>, this release requires the features and fixes from recent Vortex updates and we &lt;strong>strongly&lt;/strong> recommend only using this version of the extension with Vortex 1.2.17 &lt;em>or higher&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-note-to-mod-assistant-users">A note to Mod Assistant users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the pre-alpha release, Mod Assistant and BeatVortex had no real overlap so there was no compatibility concerns. With the new OneClick support&lt;sup>preview&lt;/sup>, we finally have our first real compatibility point: who gets launched when you open a OneClick link. Ideally, BeatVortex should not pick up OneClick links until you specifically turn it on in your settings and restart Vortex. Likewise, once you've turned it on, Vortex &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> &lt;em>replace&lt;/em> Mod Assistant to handle these links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're encountering problems with OneClick installs, I'd recommend turning off the OneClick support from whichever application you don't want handling your installs. This is still in preview so if you encounter problems, please open an issue on GitHub with as much detail as you can.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="updating-mods-for-fun-and-profit">Updating mods for fun and profit&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Beat Saber is now the first game to support Vortex's mod updates from anywhere other than Nexus Mods! We've been working with the Vortex/Nexus Mods team to test out this functionality (and &lt;a href="https://github.com/Nexus-Mods/Vortex/issues/6567">iron out the kinks&lt;/a>), but it's now possible to use Vortex's built-in updates tools without using Nexus Mods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Alpha 3.2 Release</title><link>/blog/2020/06/16/alpha-3.2-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/06/16/alpha-3.2-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release adds some new features and fixes to the &lt;a href="../../updates/v0.3.1">previous alpha release&lt;/a> including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Optional custom attributes for the Mods list: enable them from the cog in the top right.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Mods list can now display map difficulties, map modes and artist names for BeatSaver maps, right in the table.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Since this depends on new changes (below), these will only appear on maps installed after this update, or you can reinstall the map to get them now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New custom icons for difficulties and modes: please report any issues you see with these, especially with custom themes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extended installation metadata: installing mods/maps from BeatMods and BeatSaver will now preserve more metadata under the hood.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OneClick links will now auto-install custom maps: you only need to Enable new maps to add them to your install.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improvements to playlist support: installing playlists and maps should be more reliable now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Major code cleanup and refactoring: it might not be a sexy new feature, but this release cleared up a lot of convoluted and obsoleted code, so fixes and features should be a little easier now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As with &lt;a href="../../updates/v0.3.1">v0.3.1&lt;/a>, this release requires the features and fixes from recent Vortex updates and we &lt;strong>strongly&lt;/strong> recommend only using this version of the extension with Vortex 1.2.13 &lt;em>or higher&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-note-to-mod-assistant-users">A note to Mod Assistant users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the pre-alpha release, Mod Assistant and BeatVortex had no real overlap so there was no compatibility concerns. With the new OneClick support&lt;sup>preview&lt;/sup>, we finally have our first real compatibility point: who gets launched when you open a OneClick link. Ideally, BeatVortex should not pick up OneClick links until you specifically turn it on in your settings and restart Vortex. Likewise, once you've turned it on, Vortex &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> &lt;em>replace&lt;/em> Mod Assistant to handle these links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're encountering problems with OneClick installs, I'd recommend turning off the OneClick support from whichever application you don't want handling your installs. This is still in preview so if you encounter problems, please open an issue on GitHub with as much detail as you can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Alpha 3 Release</title><link>/blog/2020/06/02/alpha-3-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/06/02/alpha-3-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release marks the next full alpha of the BeatVortex extension. If you can install and test this extension, all feedback (on Nexus Mods or GitHub) is very appreciated!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release adds some big new features and fixes to the previous alpha release including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dependency tracking! Vortex will now warn you about missing dependencies when you install BeatMods mods, and offer to install them automatically.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Playlist support: BeatVortex can now install playlists, including from OneClick links, and install maps from an installed playlist.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrated OneClick Settings: settings to enable/disable OneClick link handling have been moved into the Settings page, on the Download tab.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automatic BSIPA &lt;strong>un&lt;/strong>patching: Vortex will now prompt you to revert BSIPA when you purge mods to restore things to default properly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for translations! Check the &lt;a href="../../docs/developer/translation">translation docs&lt;/a> to see how you can help translate BeatVortex into your language.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New preview feature: Playlists interface for managing installed playlists. Enable it from the Interface settings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New reworked installation logic to cut down on errors and improve metadata.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A few of the changes introduced in this release including dependencies, metaserver integration and custom mod types require some new features and fixes included in Vortex 1.2.12 and 1.2.13. As such, we &lt;strong>strongly&lt;/strong> recommend only using this version of the extension with Vortex 1.2.13 &lt;em>or higher&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dependencies">Dependencies&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As covered in the &lt;a href="../../docs/developer/dependencies">developer docs&lt;/a>, dependencies is a trickier problem than you'd think. As of 0.3.1, Vortex will warn you about missing dependencies and let you check dependencies for individual packages. It will also automatically attempt to download and install the required dependencies when you install a new mod. However, this &lt;strong>requires Vortex 1.2.13 or later&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-happened-to-030">What happened to 0.3.0?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There was briefly a 0.3.0 release, but it wasn't in a state I liked so we skipped straight to 0.3.1 with some more big changes folded in.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-note-to-mod-assistant-users">A note to Mod Assistant users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the pre-alpha release, Mod Assistant and BeatVortex had no real overlap so there was no compatibility concerns. With the new OneClick support&lt;sup>preview&lt;/sup>, we finally have our first real compatibility point: who gets launched when you open a OneClick link. Ideally, BeatVortex should not pick up OneClick links until you specifically turn it on in your settings and restart Vortex. Likewise, once you've turned it on, Vortex &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> &lt;em>replace&lt;/em> Mod Assistant to handle these links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're encountering problems with OneClick installs, I'd recommend turning off the OneClick support from whichever application you don't want handling your installs. This is still in preview so if you encounter problems, please open an issue on GitHub with as much detail as you can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Alpha 2.3 Release</title><link>/blog/2020/04/20/alpha-2.3-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/04/20/alpha-2.3-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release adds some new features and fixes to the previous alpha release including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixes bug when installing &amp;ldquo;combined&amp;rdquo; mods (see below)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adds search filtering to the BeatMods browser.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="combined-mods">&amp;ldquo;Combined&amp;rdquo; mods&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There was a bug in versions prior to 0.2.2 that would cause some mods (SongCore, for example) to fail during installation. For those interested, this bug was caused by BeatVortex detecting the song files included in a mod and assuming that the archive was a map to be deployed to &lt;code>CustomLevels&lt;/code>. This meant that any mod that included &lt;em>both&lt;/em> plugin files and map files would fail since the installer would try and deploy them to the wrong location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mods that contain map files packaged for the installation root (i.e. &lt;code>Beat Saber_Data/CustomLevels/&lt;/code>) will now be picked up as mods, rather than song maps, and be deployed correctly. Make sure you don't change the mod type for these mods as this will almost certainly break deployment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-note-to-mod-assistant-users">A note to Mod Assistant users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the pre-alpha release, Mod Assistant and BeatVortex had no real overlap so there was no compatibility concerns. With the new OneClick support&lt;sup>preview&lt;/sup>, we finally have our first real compatibility point: who gets launched when you open a OneClick link. Ideally, BeatVortex should not pick up OneClick links until you specifically turn it on in your profile and restart Vortex. Likewise, once you've turned it on, Vortex &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> &lt;em>replace&lt;/em> Mod Assistant to handle these links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're encountering problems with OneClick installs, I'd recommend turning off the OneClick support from whichever application you don't want handling your installs. This is still in preview so if you encounter problems, please open an issue on GitHub with as much detail as you can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Alpha 2.2 Release</title><link>/blog/2020/04/19/alpha-2.2-release/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/04/19/alpha-2.2-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release is a bugfix and feature release hotfix for the &lt;a href="../../blog/2020/04/17/alpha-2.1-release/">previous alpha release&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This hotfix corrects the following bugs:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The extension would attempt to register assets before loading had finished
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This &lt;em>should&lt;/em> silently fail in Vortex 1.1.x, but 1.2 will throw an error.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Huge thanks to @Pickysaurus for spotting and reporting this bug!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Alpha 2.1 Release</title><link>/blog/2020/04/17/alpha-2.1-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/04/17/alpha-2.1-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release adds some new features and fixes to the previous alpha release including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Automatic BSIPA patching: Vortex will now prompt you to run BSIPA when first deploying mods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improves stability and view layout for the BeatMods browser page&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adds compatibility filtering to the BeatMods browser for different Beat Saber versions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="a-note-to-mod-assistant-users">A note to Mod Assistant users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the pre-alpha release, Mod Assistant and BeatVortex had no real overlap so there was no compatibility concerns. With the new OneClick support&lt;sup>preview&lt;/sup>, we finally have our first real compatibility point: who gets launched when you open a OneClick link. Ideally, BeatVortex should not pick up OneClick links until you specifically turn it on in your profile and restart Vortex. Likewise, once you've turned it on, Vortex &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> &lt;em>replace&lt;/em> Mod Assistant to handle these links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're encountering problems with OneClick installs, I'd recommend turning off the OneClick support from whichever application you don't want handling your installs. This is still in preview so if you encounter problems, please open an issue on GitHub with as much detail as you can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Alpha 2 Release</title><link>/blog/2020/04/16/alpha-2-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/04/16/alpha-2-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release marks the next full alpha of the BeatVortex extension. If you can install and test this extension, all feedback (on Nexus Mods or GitHub) is very appreciated!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release adds some big new features and fixes to the previous alpha release including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>New BeatMods browser. Open the BeatMods page in the sidebar to quickly browse and install the available mods from BeatMods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved profile settings and configuration to reduce duplicate notifications and errors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Significantly better handling of mod metadata&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adds more support for ModelSaber mods (some caveats apply, check the docs)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="a-note-to-mod-assistant-users">A note to Mod Assistant users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the pre-alpha release, Mod Assistant and BeatVortex had no real overlap so there was no compatibility concerns. With the new OneClick support&lt;sup>preview&lt;/sup>, we finally have our first real compatibility point: who gets launched when you open a OneClick link. Ideally, BeatVortex should not pick up OneClick links until you specifically turn it on in your profile and restart Vortex. Likewise, once you've turned it on, Vortex &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> &lt;em>replace&lt;/em> Mod Assistant to handle these links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're encountering problems with OneClick installs, I'd recommend turning off the OneClick support from whichever application you don't want handling your installs. This is still in preview so if you encounter problems, please open an issue on GitHub with as much detail as you can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Alpha Release</title><link>/blog/2020/04/08/alpha-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/04/08/alpha-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release is the first full alpha of the BeatVortex extension. If you can install and test this extension, all feedback (on Nexus Mods or GitHub) is very appreciated!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release adds a ton of missing features from the initial pre-alpha including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Preview support for OneClick installs from BeatSaver and BeastSaber&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved handling of game mods to improve deployments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supports pulling mod metadata from BeatSaver and BeatMods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved download support that should improve installs from BeatMods/BeatSaver&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configurable profile features&lt;sup>preview&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved metadata handling including covers for maps, where available&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Major under-the-hood refactorings that should improve performance and cut down on errors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="a-note-to-mod-assistant-users">A note to Mod Assistant users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the pre-alpha release, Mod Assistant and BeatVortex had no real overlap so there was no compatibility concerns. With the new OneClick support&lt;sup>preview&lt;/sup>, we finally have our first real compatibility point: who gets launched when you open a OneClick link. Ideally, BeatVortex should not pick up OneClick links until you specifically turn it on in your profile and restart Vortex. Likewise, once you've turned it on, Vortex &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> &lt;em>replace&lt;/em> Mod Assistant to handle these links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're encountering problems with OneClick installs, I'd recommend turning off the OneClick support from whichever application you don't want handling your installs. This is still in preview so if you encounter problems, please open an issue on GitHub with as much detail as you can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Initial Release</title><link>/blog/2020/03/31/initial-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/03/31/initial-release/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This release is now available &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">on Nexus Mods&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This release is the first pre-alpha of the BeatVortex extension. While you can install this release into Vortex, be aware that it's functionality is &lt;em>very&lt;/em> limited in this version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mods will be installed and deployed, but install behaviour is not well-defined and you may encounter some unhandled issues. Additionally, this release only supports installing mods from archives and does not support mod metadata. These will be added in future releases.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>