<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BeatVortex – Usage</title><link>/docs/usage/</link><description>Recent content in Usage on BeatVortex</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/docs/usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Installing BeatVortex</title><link>/docs/usage/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/usage/installation/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="installing-beatvortex">Installing BeatVortex&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There's a couple of different ways to install BeatVortex! Unless you've got a pretty specific use case, you'll probably want one of the two automatic methods, but manual installation is available as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="automatic-installation">Automatic Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is the easiest way to install!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Open up Vortex, and open the Extensions panel from the left sidebar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Find more&lt;/strong> to open the list of Extensions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>Beat Saber Support&lt;/strong> and click &lt;em>Install&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the extension to install and &lt;strong>restart Vortex&lt;/strong> when prompted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../install_1.png" alt="installation process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once Vortex has restarted, just click the Manage button on Beat Saber in your Games screen and you're ready to &lt;a href="../../docs/usage/mods">install some mods&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="semi-automatic-installation">Semi-Automatic Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you can't install directly from the Extensions screen, you can instead install from the archive.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Download the archive from &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">Nexus Mods&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://https://github.com/agc93/beatvortex/releases">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the Extensions panel in Vortex&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;em>Drop File(s)&lt;/em> box in the corner and locate the archive you downloaded.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the extension to install and &lt;strong>restart Vortex&lt;/strong> when prompted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once Vortex has restarted, just click the Manage button on Beat Saber in your Games screen and you're ready to &lt;a href="../../docs/usage/mods">install some mods&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="manual-installation">Manual Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Only attempt this if you &lt;em>absolutely&lt;/em> have to. It becomes much harder to debug and much harder to upgrade.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you want to install the extension yourself, you will have to install the actual extension files manually. Make sure you close Vortex before proceeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, download the archive from &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/96?tab=files">Nexus Mods&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://https://github.com/agc93/beatvortex/actions">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, unpack the archive to somewhere convenient. You should have a directory named &lt;code>game-beatsaber&lt;/code> with four files inside:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>info.json&lt;/li>
&lt;li>index.js&lt;/li>
&lt;li>gameart.png&lt;/li>
&lt;li>beatModsList.scss&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now, copy the whole directory to your Vortex folder. You can easily open your Vortex folder by opening a new File Explorer window and entering the following in to the location bar: &lt;code>%APPDATA%/Vortex&lt;/code> and then opening the &lt;code>plugins&lt;/code> directory (create it if it doesn’t exist).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you’re done, you should have four files at the following locations:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">C:\Users\&amp;lt;your-user-name-here&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming\Vortex\plugins\game-beatsaber\info.json
C:\Users\&amp;lt;your-user-name-here&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming\Vortex\plugins\game-beatsaber\index.js
C:\Users\&amp;lt;your-user-name-here&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming\Vortex\plugins\game-beatsaber\gameart.png
C:\Users\&amp;lt;your-user-name-here&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming\Vortex\plugins\game-beatsaber\beatModsList.scss
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>With those files in place, you're clear to start Vortex and you should see the Beat Saber icon in the Games screen light up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Installing Mods</title><link>/docs/usage/mods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/usage/mods/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>BeatVortex 0.2.1 (and later) includes beta support for prompting when an IPA patch is needed and automatically running it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you haven't already run IPA for your current install, you should be prompted to run it after your first deploy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>At it's core, installing mods is roughly the same as any Vortex-enabled game, just without the convenience of installing from Nexus Mods. Make sure you've added Beat Saber as a managed game in Vortex.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you haven't already, open the Games screen and click the &lt;strong>Manage&lt;/strong> button on the Beat Saber icon under &lt;em>Unmanaged&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>There's a few main ways to install mods:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>OneClick installs&lt;sup>&lt;em>preview&lt;/em>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>BeatMods Browser&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download in Vortex&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install from archives&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="oneclick-installationsuppreviewsup">OneClick Installation&lt;sup>&lt;em>preview&lt;/em>&lt;/sup>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One-click installation of custom songs from BeastSaber, BeatSaver or ModelSaber requires first enabling it in your Vortex settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Enabling one-click installs in Vortex will most likely prevent Mod Assistant from handling one-click installs!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>From the Settings screen, open the Download tab and scroll down to the &amp;ldquo;Enable OneClick Installations&amp;rdquo; section. Check the boxes to enable OneClick installations for maps or custom models (or both!). You can also toggle these back off to &amp;ldquo;unregister&amp;rdquo; Vortex for handling these links.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../enableOCI.gif" alt="installation process">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You &lt;em>should&lt;/em> see this change immediately, but if you're having problems, try restarting Vortex&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Open up BeatSaver/BeastSaber/ModelSaber and click any of the OneClick install links: Vortex should pick up the link in the background, fetch the song details and download the map (or mod) directly into your mod list. Install and Enable as per usual to deploy into your game.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="a-note-on-modelsaber-installs">A note on ModelSaber installs&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Since ModelSaber models are not distributed as archives but just raw files, Vortex will warn you and will create a mod archive with just that one file. All of Vortex's install and deployments logic really works best with archives.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="beatmods-browser">BeatMods Browser&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you're looking to install any of the mods listed on BeatMods, you can easily do so from the BeatMods page in the sidebar (available from v0.2.0 onwards). This will list all approved mods for your current game version and you can quickly install them using the &lt;em>Ready to Install&lt;/em> button on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that since Vortex can't tell which Beat Saber versions are mod-compatible (i.e. 1.8.0 mods work in 1.9.0), you may have to manually choose a version using the switcher at the top of the page to see all available mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>BeatVortex &lt;em>should&lt;/em> automatically prompt you to install dependencies when you install BeatMods mods from the browser. You can also check the Dependencies column of the Mods list to see what your mods need.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../installBeatMods.gif" alt="beatmods installation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="download-in-vortex">Download in Vortex&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you've added Beat Saber, you can jump over to the usual Mods screen using the menu on the left. You might not have any mods here, but if you click on the &lt;em>But don't worry, I know a place&amp;hellip;&lt;/em> dropdown, you'll get the choice of installing from BeatMods, BeatSaver or BeastSaber.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This option will move to the &lt;em>Get more mods&lt;/em> drop-down after you have installed your first mod.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You can browse mods using the built-in browser that appears and if you download the ZIP archive of any song (from BeatSaver/BeastSaber), mod (from BeatMods), or model (from ModelSaber), Vortex will attempt to install it in the background for you. Close the browser to go back to your mod list then Install and Enable your mods as usual to use them in-game.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="install-from-archives">Install from archives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can also download mod/map archives directly from BeastSaber, BeatSaver, BeatMods, #pc-mods or anywhere else you like and install them with Vortex. Simply use the &lt;em>Install From File&lt;/em> button in the toolbar or drop them onto the drop zone at the bottom of the Vortex window.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Be aware that installing from archives will often not include the full metadata so mods may be confusingly named. Double-click the mod in the mod list to change its name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Please note that &amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo; mods that aren't packaged in an archive (for example, plain &lt;code>dll&lt;/code> files provided by some GitHub projects or #pc-mods posts) will &lt;em>not&lt;/em> work! Vortex only supports installing from archives so just add the file to a ZIP and install that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="updating-mods">Updating Mods&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This feature is available in preview for &lt;a href="../../updates/v0.3.3">v0.3.3&lt;/a> or later&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In the latest versions of BeatVortex, you can enable support for BeatMods updates in the Preview Settings. You can then use the normal &amp;ldquo;Check for Updates&amp;rdquo; button in the Mods list to immediately check all your installed BeatMods mods for updates and optionally update them in one-click. This will also preserve the old version in your Mods list!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mod updates are a new feature that have not necessarily been fully tested, so please report any bugs or issues you find.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Configuration</title><link>/docs/usage/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/usage/configuration/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="customising-metadata">Customising metadata&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can customise the basic metadata of any of your mods (name, author, notes etc) using Vortex's built-in sidebar. Just double-click on the name of any mod in your mod list and you'll get a small dialog where you can change the name and author, or add some notes for yourself. It's not recommended to change the source or mod type as these control how mods are handled internally.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="profiles">Profiles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Just like any other Vortex game, you can have multiple profiles configured for different mod selections. Don't want your streaming mods enabled when you're offline? Set up two profiles and switch over when you're playing with an audience. You can create a new profile from the Profiles screen by either cloning your exising one (from the Edit dropdown menu), or clicking &lt;em>Add &amp;ldquo;Beat Saber&amp;rdquo; Profile&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="removing-or-resetting-beatvortex">Removing or resetting BeatVortex&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you want to completely reset BeatVortex so that you can start over from scratch, first uninstall all your currently installed mods from the Mods list. Once you've done that (and deployed!) jump to the Profiles screen, and choose &lt;em>Remove&lt;/em> from the dropdown menu beside the edit button for the &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>Beat Saber - Default&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; profile. This will effectively reset your Vortex so that Beat Saber will reappear as an available, unmanaged game in the Games list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To remove BeatVortex entirely, you should uninstall and remove all your installed mods from the Mods list first. After deploying, you can then remove the Default profile (see above), and finally uninstall the extension itself by clicking over to the Extensions screen. BeatVortex will appear near the end of the list as &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>Game: Beat Saber&lt;/strong>&amp;quot;. Click Remove to uninstall BeatVortex.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note that Beat Saber will still show up in your Games list since Vortex can redownload the extension from Nexus Mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="purging-to-default">Purging to default&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you want to take your game back to a default, unmodded state, you can use Vortex's &lt;em>Purge&lt;/em> feature. Click the Purge Mods button from the Mods list and Vortex will undeploy all your enabled mods, leaving your game directory essentially unmodded.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You should be prompted to revert BSIPA patching when you purge, and prompted to rerun patching when you next deploy mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="preview-features">Preview Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We sometimes include early previews of new features for BeatVortex that might not be fully ready for primetime. These features are usually functional, but are also usually still in active development and not necessarily as polished as you might expect. You can enable any of these features to get early access to new functionality, but be warned that you will probably see bugs and problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To check and enable preview features, open the Interface tab of your Settings page and scroll down to find the &amp;ldquo;BeatVortex Preview Features&amp;rdquo; section.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="categories">Categories&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This feature is currently in preview!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When you first start managing Beat Saber (or after the update to v0.3.3 for existing users), BeatVortex will pull down the current set of categories from BeatMods. The next time you start Vortex, you should be able to sort, filter and group your mods by category so you can just check your Stream Tools or hide the Tools for Modders.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="handling-your-mods-list">Handling your Mods list&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Since everything gets installed as a mod when you're using BeatVortex, your Mods list can get quite lengthy quite fast! Here's a few tips for keeping your mods list more manageable:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>One of the best options is to group your mods list by source. This will let you look at your BeatMods mods, BeatSaver maps, ModelSaber models, and BeastSaber playlists as convenient groups. Click the small list icon beside the Source column to enable grouping.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remember you can easily add or remove columns from the mod list using the small cog in the top right. You can remove builtin columns (like endorsement) and even add in Beat Saber-specific columns (like artist name or map difficulties).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Double clicking any mod will bring up the details pane for that mod. You can use this to edit any missing information, or just to add your own notes about a particular mod or map.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Installing Playlists</title><link>/docs/usage/playlists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/usage/playlists/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>BeatVortex 0.3.1 or later is required to install playlists using Vortex.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're currently using Beatlist for playlists, see below for extra information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Playlist support in BeatVortex is very new and very experimental! The notion of playlists isn't something that easily maps into the Vortex way of handling things so there might be some rough patches.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-playlists">Creating Playlists&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This feature is available in v0.3.3 or later&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You can now create your own playlists from the maps you already have installed! Just select multiple BeatSaver maps from your Mods list (hold Ctrl and click) and select Create Playlists from the bar at the bottom of the screen. You'll be prompted to name your playlist and optionally give it an image. BeatVortex will then create a playlist based on those maps and let you save it to a local file. You can also immediately install it so you can deploy and manage like your other playlists.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="enabling-playlist-installation">Enabling Playlist Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To enable installing playlists with Vortex, check the &amp;ldquo;Enable OneClick links for playlists&amp;rdquo; option in the Download tab of the Settings page. When you click a OneClick link for a playlist, it should be automatically downloaded and installed into Vortex and will give you the option of immediately installing all the maps from that playlist.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This can take a while for large playlists! Check the Downloads page to see your progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Playlists will have their own entry in your Mods list so you can edit or remove the playlist without affecting all the songs in the playlist.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="preview-feature-playlists-view">Preview Feature: Playlists view&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have also included a &lt;em>very&lt;/em> early release of a basic Playlists management interface as a preview feature in the latest extension versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enable it, head over to the Interface tab of the Settings page and look for &amp;ldquo;BeatVortex Preview Features&amp;rdquo;. Check &amp;ldquo;Enable Playlists Management&amp;rdquo; on to enable the new interface, and you should see the new page appear in the sidebar.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sometimes you'll need to open your Mods list again to have it show up!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This will allow you to quickly list and inspect the playlists you have installed and deployed locally, as well as check the details of any songs included in the playlist. You can also use the button at the top right to immediately install the whole playlist (or just the maps you don't already have).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feature is &lt;em>very new&lt;/em> and there's certain to be some bugs. If you do enable the feature and encounter any bugs, please report them &lt;a href="https://github.com/agc93/beatvortex/issues">on GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="beatlist-users">Beatlist Users&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you're currently using Beatlist for managing your playlists, I &lt;em>strongly&lt;/em> recommend sticking with it! BeatVortex will likely never support the same features as Beatlist, nor have the same level of polish or user-friendliness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you do want to use Vortex to manage your playlists, just be aware that enabling playlist handling in your Vortex settings will stop Beatlist from automatically handling playlist install links (it will also prevent Mod Assistant from handling them). You &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> be able to continue using Beatlist to view and manage your playlist library, but this has not been tested (at all!) and might lead to some weirdness.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="mod-assistant-users">Mod Assistant Users&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you're currently using Mod Assistant to install your playlists, you should also be aware of a few things:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Enabling playlist link handling in your Vortex settings will likely prevent Mod Assistant from handling those links.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Installing a playlist with Vortex will separately install each song in the playlist as a manageable mod in Vortex.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: BeatVortex for Mod Assistant Users</title><link>/docs/usage/mod-assistant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/usage/mod-assistant/</guid><description>
&lt;p>First and foremost, the best advice for Mod Assistant users is this: if you don't want to change, &lt;strong>you don't have to!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BeatVortex is a completely unofficial project and is &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> intended as a replacement to Mod Assistant, which is also a very good way of handling Beat Saber mods. If you're happy with Mod Assistant and don't have any preference for using Vortex, don't feel like you need to make the switch!&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This document assumes a basic understanding of Vortex and its concepts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For help with Vortex, check out the &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/about/vortex/">Vortex Support page&lt;/a> or use the Knowledge Base page inside Vortex.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="basic-differences">Basic Differences&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the biggest differences when modding Beat Saber with Vortex is a consequence of how Vortex works: &lt;em>everything is a mod&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That means that when using BeatVortex, every map is a mod, every custom saber is a mod, every playlist is a mod, and every plugin is a mod. While that sounds daunting, it also means you can easily manage every part of your installation from the one place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, even songs installed using OneClick links will install as a fully manageable mod in Vortex that can be enabled, disabled and deployed to your install directory like any other mod.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="state-and-deployments">State and Deployments&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The other thing worth remembering if you're coming from Mod Assistant is that everything you do in Vortex happens in a staging folder first. Your mods and maps are all installed and enabled from your staging folder. It's not until you &lt;em>Deploy&lt;/em> your mods that the changes happen in your installation directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, when Mod Assistant starts up it loads your current mods directly from the installation directory each time. In Vortex, your Mods list is the state of your staging folder and your changes are made to the installation directory when you deploy your mods.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="oneclick-installation">OneClick Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have added &lt;em>preview&lt;/em> support for OneClick installation links for maps, custom models and playlists, but this is a quite new feature! They are also not enabled by default: you can enable OneClick links for any specific mod type (or all of them) from the Download tab of your Vortex settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike Mod Assistant, which doesn't &amp;ldquo;track&amp;rdquo; maps or playlists installed with OneClick links, Vortex will handle OneClick links like any other installation: the map/model/mod is installed as a complete mod, manageable from your Mods list and then deployed to your install directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bsipa">BSIPA&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Some of the features that BSIPA provides overlap a bit with Vortex and BeatVortex's feature sets, so it's worth knowing a few things first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one, Mod Assistant installs mods into a special &lt;code>IPA/Pending&lt;/code> folder and BSIPA then &amp;ldquo;installs&amp;rdquo; them into the main game directory. Vortex installs its files into the mod staging folder, then deploys them directly into the game install folder. This means that while you can install new mods or updates into your Vortex while Beat Saber is running you shouldn't deploy them.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In fact, if you launched Beat Saber with Vortex, it will pause deployments until you close the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="compatibility">Compatibility&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While I don't recommend it, it should be possible to use BeatVortex &lt;em>alongside&lt;/em> Mod Assistant, BeatList or any other modding tools. This is not something I actively test and Vortex will likely react in funny ways to changes made by the other tools, but it shouldn't break anything major.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you do end up using BeatVortex side-by-side with Mod Assistant or other tools, please report any issues you see.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Of particular note: only enable OneClick links in &lt;strong>one&lt;/strong> tool. If you want to use Mod Assistant to install maps with OneClick, enable it in Mod Assistant's settings and &lt;strong>do not&lt;/strong> enable it in Vortex's settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="support">Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As covered in the &lt;a href="../../docs/introduction/faq">FAQ&lt;/a>, BeatVortex is not supported by any of Nexus Mods, the Vortex team, or the Beat Saber Modding Group. BeatVortex is exclusively a community project, currently run by one not-a-real-developer, so please don't complain to anyone from Nexus or BSMG if things don't work quite right.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>